

Mariia Danilova

QA Engineer (manual) remotely

Parcelona, Spain danilova.maria.k@gmail.com

+34615666088

Profile

I am a Manual QA with a background in market research, two years of crowd testing experience, and current freelancing on a SaaS startup project. I use my eye, hands and tools like Chrome DevTools and Postman to ensure product quality and functionality.

In light of my soft skills, I mention empathy, resilience, attention to details, and assessing the product from the end-user's perspective.

Employment History

Feb 2023 — Present

QA specialist (part-time work) at Winware.ai

remote

- Created test cases and tracked issues using Jira-Xray
- Conducted manual testing (smoke, regression, sanity)
- · Maintained accurate documentation
- · Performed API testing (CRUD requests)
- Worked with Agile methodologies, particularly Kanban

Jan 2021

Crowd tester at Testbirds GmbH

online

- Conducted approximately 30 tests (structure bug testing, payment flow analysis, exploratory testing, mobile app testing)
- · Used bug tracking system
- · Created bug reported

Oct 2007 — Feb 2013

Moscow

Senior Researcher/Research Project Manager (Healthcare market) at GfK Rus

- Conducted ad-hoc research, developed research strategies, including design, scheduling, and cost estimation.
- · Crafted research tools, such as samples, questionnaires, and specifications for field, encoding, and data processing departments.
- · Produced comprehensive analysis reports and client presentations.
- · Conducted end-to-end market research for such clients as Novartis, GSK, Shering Plau, Elly Lilly, Pfizer etc.

Education

Sep 1997 — Jun 2003

Saint Petersburg State University

Saint Petersburg

Master's Degree in Sociology

Links

Linkedin

GitHub

Skills

Chrome DevTools

Postman

GIT

Jira, Trello, TestRail

SQL

Python (basics)

Android Studio

Charles

Docker

English (B2), Spanish (B1), Russian